Register of the Tibor Eckhardt papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Tibor Eckhardt papers
1921-1972
80026
Hoover Institution Archives
24 manuscript boxes (10.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, notes, memoranda, clippings and other printed matter relating to twentieth-century Hungarian politics, anti-communist movements in the United States, and Hungarian émigré politics.
Eckhardt, Tibor, 1888-1972.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual or digital material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1888 October 26 Born, Makó, Hungary
1908 Doctor of Law, Peter Pazmany University of Sciences, Budapest, Hungary Doctor of Law, University of Berlin, Germany
pre-1914 Served in the Royal Hungarian Ministry of Interior
1914-1918 Attached to the General Staff of the Austro-Hungarian Army and the Administration of Transylvania
1919 Organized active resistance with police force against the communist regime of Bela Kun in Hungary
1920 Chief of Press Section, Hungarian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, later in the Prime Minister's Office
1922 Elected to the Hungarian Parliament as member of the Government Party
1923 Went into opposition against the conservative government
1929-1930 Visited the United States upon the invitation of President Butler of Columbia University; lectured at American universities under the auspices of the Carnegie Endowment
1930 Founded the Hungarian Small Holders' Party and became its leader
1934-1935 Chief Delegate of Hungary to the League of Nations, Geneva
1935 Leader of the democratic opposition in Hungary
1940 Visited the United States for the second time, received by President Roosevelt, who invited him to come to the United States in case Hungary was overrun by the Nazis
1941 August 8 Arrived in the United States
1941 September Founded the "Movement for Independent Hungary"
1941-1945 Collaborated with the U.S. State Department
1948 Participated in organizing the Hungarian National Council and accepted membership in its Executive Committee
1954 Resigned from the Executive Committee of the Hungarian National Council Participated in organizing the Assembly of Captive European Nations and became Chairman of its Hungarian delegation
1956 October Launched the organization "First Aid for Hungary," with Herbert Hoover as Honorary Chairman
1972 September 10 Died, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, notes, memoranda, clippings and other printed matter relating to twentieth-century Hungarian politics, anti-communist movements in the United States, and Hungarian émigré politics.
Anti-communist movements--United States.; Hungarians--United States.; Hungary--Politics and government--20th century.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1921-1972 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical data and personal documents, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Articles on Eckhardt, 1938-1968 (Box 1)
  - Attacks upon Eckhardt
    - General, 1921-1967
    - On communist infiltration of American-Hungarian organizations
  - Defense of Eckhardt, 1942-1954
  - Extensions of stay in the United States, and American citizenship, 1945-1954
  - Resignation from the Executive Committee of the Hungarian National Council, 1954
  - Well wishes when in hospital, 1972
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1941-1972 (Boxes 1-3)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - America: National Catholic Weekly, N.Y., 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - American Foundation for Hungarian Literature and Education, Ltd., N.Y., 1971
  - American Hungarian Federation, Washington, D.C., 1970
  - American Hungarian Federation of Churches and Societies of Youngstown, Ohio, 1942
  - American Lithuanian Council, N.Y., 1958
  - Apor, Baron Gabor, 1959
  - Associated Clubs, Inc., Princeton, N.J., 1951
  - Austrian American Federation, Inc., N.Y., 1969
  - Babo de Vagvecse, Baron Tivadar, 1952-1957 (Box 2)
  - Bachkay, Bela, 1958-1971
  - Balassa, Bela, 1950
  - Balkunas, John, 1958
  - Balogh de Almas, Dezso, 1942
  - Barcza, Ferenc, undated
  - Beliczey, Miklos, 1970
  - Bessenyey, Gabor de, 1951
  - Bethlen, Count Istvan, 1941-1944
  - Beukema, Col. Herman, 1950
  - Boros, Ladislas, undated
  - Borshy-Kerekes, Gyorgy E., 1958
  - Broich-Oppert, Georg von, 1957
  - Brooklyn Alumni Sodality, 1955
  - Caracasi Magyarok Barati Kore, 1951
  - Chiang Kai-shek, Madame (Mayling Soong Chiang), 1950
  - Comite der Soforthilfe fur Ungarn, Vienna, 1957
  - Council on Foreign Relations, N.Y., 1941
  - Csonka, Emil, 1968-1969
  - Czermann, Antal, 1952-1953
  - Czikann-Zichy, Moriz, 1951
  - Daruvar, Yves de, 1972
  - Emmet, Christopher, 1958
  - Eross, Ferenc, 1951
  - Fabian, Bela, 1956
  - Fabry, Dr., 1952
  - Geber, Antal, 1941-1942
  - Georgian Association in the United States of America, N.Y., 1959
  - Gereben, Istvan, 1972
  - Ghika, George, 1950
  - Gower, Margaret, 1947-1948
  - Habsburg, Archduke Otto von, 1951-1969
  - Hartmann, Janos, 1951
  - Havas, Eugene, 1941
  - Hennyey, General Gusztav, 1950-1970
  - Hokky, Karoly, 1963
  - Horthy de Nagybanya, Miklos, Jr., 1957
  - Huzianyi, Stephen, 1942
  - International Commission of Jurists, The Hague, 1957
  - Jako, Geza J., undated
  - Jancso, Livia, 1964
  - Jelic, Branimir R., 1963-1964
  - Kanadai Magyarok Szovetsege, Toronto, 1963
  - Kardos-Talbot, Bela, 1970
  - Kereszteny Nemzeti Ujjaszuletes Partja, Solothurn, Switzerland, 1957
  - Kertesz, Istvan, 1949
  - Kirkconnell, Watson, 1947
  - Kresz, Geza, 1956
  - Krudy, Ferenc, 1972
  - Kuthy, Jose, 1942
  - Lengyel, Bela, 1957
  - Lukacs, Janos, 1965
  - McFadden, H. M., 1951-1953
  - Mallon, Winifred, 1946
  - Marosy, Ferenc, 1957-1972
  - Mester, Klaus, 1970-1971
  - Mikes, Imre, 1948
  - Mindszenty, Cardinal Joseph, 1971
  - Montgomery, John Flornoy, 1944-1954
  - Nadas, Janos, 1962
  - The New School of Social Work, Columbia University, 1957
  - Nyaradi, Miklos, 1952-1971
  - Olah, Gyorgy, 1970-1971
  - Onody, Dezso, 1962
  - Overseas Rotary Fellowship, N.Y., 1956-1958
  - Palffy, Jozsef, 1952-1953
  - Pasztor, Laszlo, 1972
  - Pelenyi, Janos, 1950
  - Peyer, Karoly, 1954
  - Pogany, Andras, 1966-1970
  - Radnoczy, A. von, undated
  - Revay, Count Istvan, 1958-1972
  - Riposanu, Pamfil A., 1958
  - Ronai, Zoltan A., undated
  - Rupprecht, Pal, 1963
  - Scitovszky, Tibor, 1953
  - Sevilla-Sacasa, Guillermo, 1957
  - Sulyok, Dezso, 1962
  - Szegedi-Maszak, Aladar, 1945
  - Sztankovich, V. E. A., 1944
  - Tamas, Andras, 1944 (Box 3)
  - Tollas, Tibor, 1969
  - Toth, Laszlo, 1963
  - Ugocsay-Geletey, Janos, 1962
  - Ullein-Reviczky, Antal, 1953
  - Union Familia Escolapia Cubana, Inc., N.Y., 1968
  - U.S. Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1970
  - U.S. War Department, General Staff, Military Intelligence Division G-2, Washington, D.C., 1944
  - Varga, Laszlo, 1958-1962
  - Veres, General Lajos, 1970
  - Wellesley College Forum, Massachusetts, 1956
  - Zilahy, Lajos, 1963
  - Zsolnay, Nicholas M., 1971
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1922-1972 (Boxes 3-5)
  Arranged alphabetically by title within those two categories.
  - Speeches
    - Untitled - Miscellaneous notes, handwritten
      - Undated (Box 3)
      - 1949
      - 1951
      - 1954
      - 1959
      - 1968
      - 1970
    - "Africa," address at the Hungarian Piarist Congress, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1956 December 4
    - All American Conference to Combat Communism, Seventh Annual Meeting, Omaha, Nebraska, 1957 November 9-10
    - "America the Last Hope of the World," speech delivered on several different occasions, handwritten notes, 1950-1952
    - American foreign policy from a European point of view, Y.M.C.A., handwritten notes
    - American Hungarian Literary Society, Ronconcoma, N.Y., handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1966 March 19
    - Aradi Vertanuk Emlekunnepelye. Meghivo, Az unnepi beszed szovege hianyzik (invitation), Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1960 October 15
    - Assembly of Captive European Nations, plenary meetings, First Session, Carnegie Endowment International Center, N.Y., 1954 September 20-21
    - "Behodolas, vagy fwelszabadulas" (Surrender of liberation), speech on the 5th anniversary of the founding of the Hungarian Helicon, Toronto, Canada, 1956 April 7
      Handwritten notes, clippings, and correspondence in English and Hungarian.
    - "Brandt tevedesei" (The errors of Brandt), handwritten notes
    - Bridgeport, Connecticut, speech outlines, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1968 January 5
    - "The Direct Communist Action in the Satellite Countries," Knights of Columbus, New York State Council, handwritten notes, 1946 November 26
    - "Az Egyesult Europa, 1963" (The United Europe, 1963), The Szechenyi Istvan Society, Inc., N.Y., handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1963 October 23
    - Erdelyi Magyar Kozmuvelodesi Egyesulet - EMKE (Hungarian Transylvanian Cultural Association), 75th year jubilee celebration, handwritten and typewritten notes in Hungarian
    - France and European unity, Overseas Rotary Fellowship, N.Y., handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1960 May 7
    - "Hogy veszett el Erdely?" (How Transylvania was lost?), American Hungarian Federation, Eastern District, N.Y., typewritten text and clipping in Hungarian, 1959 December 5
    - Hungary, Parliament, House of Representatives
      - Excerpts from speeches and notes, typewritten in Hungarian, 1922-1926
      - Stenographic records, photocopies in Hungarian
        - Speeches and notes
          - 1931
          - 1932
          - 1933
          - 1934
          - 1935
          - 1936
          - 1937
          - 1938
          - 1939
        - Speeches against election frauds, 1931-1935, 1937-1938
        - Speeches concerning the Jewish question, 1938-1939
    - Leones Cubanos en el Exilio, Centenario del Grito de Yara (Centenary of the Independence Day of Cuba), banquet, N.Y., handwritten notes, 1968 October 6
    - Luncheon given by Mr. and Mrs. James Beck, N.Y., handwritten notes and typewritten list of main points of speech, 1947 April 29
    - Magyar Cserkeszet (Hungarian Boyscouts), 60th Anniversary, N.Y., handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1970 May 16
    - Magyar Cserkeszszoevetseg Nagytanacsa (General Council of the Hungarian Scout Association in Exile), reunion commemorating the 25th anniversary of the death of Count Paul Teleki, N.Y., 1966 March 31
    - Magyar Helikon Tarsasag (Hungarian Helikon Society), Toronto, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1971 December 11
    - Magyar Piarista Kongresszus (Hungarian Piarist Congress), handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1959 February 1
    - Magyar Radiobeszed Valasztas (Hungarian radio speech, election), handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1968 October 19
    - "Magyarorszag es a Szabad Vilag" (Hungary and the Free World), Cleveland, Ohio, 1957 December 14
      Handwritten notes, correspondence in Hungarian, and typewritten excerpts in English.
    - "A Magyarsag 1970-ben nem unnepelhet" (The Hungarians must not celebrate in 1970), St. Stephen Memorial Committee Conference, N.Y., clippings in Hungarian
      - 1st part, "Hungary will turn into a battlefield in case of war,", January 24-25; (3 folders)
      - 2nd part, "The struggle without principles has been going on since June 1942,", February 22; (2 folders)
    - Marcius 15, 1848 (March 15 - National Holiday)
      - Handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1947 March 13 (Box 4)
      - Freedom Festival, N.Y., typewritten text in Hungarian, 1958 March 16
      - Mikoyan's visit to the United States, Bridgeport, Connecticut, typewritten text in Hungarian, 1959 March 15
      - Freedom Festival, N.Y., handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1960 March 13
      - Canadian Hungarian Federation, Toronto and Hamilton, Canada, handwritten notes and clippings in Hungarian, 1963 March 17
      - Freedom Festival, N.Y., handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1966 March 13
      - Hungarian Committee of Norwalk and Its Region, South Norwalk, Connecticut, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1968 March 10
      - Canadian Hungarian Federation, Toronto, Canada, handwritten notes and clippings in Hungarian, 1968 March 17
      - Handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1970?
      - Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation of Canada, Petofi Commemoration Dinner, Toronto, Canada, handwritten notes and clippings in Hungarian, 1970 March 14
      - Hungarian Cultural Club of Oshawa, Canada, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1970 March 15
    - "Mikent kerult Erdely ketszer is roman kezre?" (How has Transylvania fallen twice under the Romanians?), American Hungarian Federation, New York Chapter, clippings in Hungarian, 1966 January 15
    - "Mistakes of Peacemaking," Bradley University, Peoria, Illinois, handwritten notes, 1953 November 2
    - "A Nemet-Szovjet Szerzodes megkotesenek hatasa Europa jovojere" (The effects of German Soviet treaty on the future of Europe), American Hungarian Federation, New York Chapter, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1970 October 24
    - New Brunswick, New Jersey, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1968 November 3
    - "The North Atlantic Pact and World Peace," Easton, Pennsylvania, Chicago, Washington, D.C., handwritten notes, 1949 October, November 20?; 1953 February 21
    - October 23, 1956 - Anniversary Celebration
      - Our Lady of Hungary Rectory, Welland, Ontario, Canada, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1957 October 27
      - Magyar Harcosok Bajtarsi Kozossege, Newark, New Jersey, handwritten notes and clippings, 1959 October 18
      - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1959 October 25
      - Passaic, New Jersey, clipping in Hungarian, 1960 October
      - World Federation of Hungarian Freedom Fighters, New York Chapter, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1968 October 20
    - "One World and the Basic Human Rights," Johnstown, Pennsylvania, handwritten notes, 1950 February 8
    - "Az orosz veszedelem" (The Russian danger), handwritten notes and clippings in Hungarian, 1968 October
    - "Peacemaking," Georgetown University, Senior Class Dinner and Pathfinders Club, Washington, D.C., handwritten notes, 1946 November 13
    - "Political Disintegration of Europe," a series of lectures, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., handwritten notes, 1946 January 31 - May 23
    - Republican rally, Elizabeth, New Jersey, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 196? July 20
    - Szechenyi Istvan Emlekvacsora (Istvan Szechenyi Memorial Dinner), N.Y., published text in Hungarian, 1955 December 2
    - "Szent Korona sorsa" (Fate of the Holy Crown), American Hungarian Federation, New York Chapter, handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1970 May 24
    - Szuletesnapi beszed a 80-ik szuletesnapon (Birthday address on the 80th birthday of Eckhardt), handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1968
    - Teleki Pal grofol, emlekbeszed a Magyar Cserkesz Szovetseg Nagytanacsa megalakulasa alkalmabol (Memorial address about Count Pal Teleki, delivered on the occasion of the founding of the Grand Council of the General Council of the Hungarian Scout Association in Exile), N.Y., 1963 April 29
    - "Varhatunk-e valtozast a nemzetkozi politikaban es Magyarorszagon 1966-ban?" (Can we expect a change in the international politics and in Hungary in 1966?), Federation of Free Hungarian Jurists roundtable conference, Carnegie Endowment Center, N.Y., printed text and clippings, 1966 March 11
  - Writings
    - Untitled
      - Historical events in Hungary, incomplete manuscript, part handwritten and part typewritten
      - Memorandum, handwritten draft to the White House, 1969 January 24
        It became the basis of the memorandum presented to Henry Kissinger by the American Hungarian Federation on March 21, 1969.
      - Notes and comments, handwritten
        - Agriculture - Hungary
        - Benes, Eduard
        - China
        - Democracy
        - Ein Kaiser Kampft fur die Freiheit, by Ludwig Windisch-Graetz
        - Khrushchev's visit to the United States in August 1958
        - Vilaghoditok, by Lajos Marschalko
    - "Alarm," published article in German, 1968 October-November
    - "An Alternative to EDC," typescript of full text and summary, 1954 January 11
    - "American Policy in Europe, Memorandum on," handwritten and typewritten copies, 1970 January 15
    - "Amerika es az europai egyseg," unpublished memorandum, carbon copy typescript, 1948 October 23
    - "A brit birodalmi politika magyar vonatkozasarol. Vazlat" (The British imperial politics and their Hungarian relations), draft, carbon copy typescript, 1946 September 15
    - "Defense of Europe," handwritten notes (Box 5)
    - "Drop the R Please, Mr. President," handwritten notes
    - "Az egyseg utja" (The road of unity), typescript
    - "Foreign Aid, Memorandum," handwritten draft and typescript, 1960 July 29
    - "The Ghost of Teheran," handwritten notes
    - "Hogyan veszett el Erdely?" (How Transylvania was lost?)
      - Original handwritten manuscript
      - Published article in two parts, 1968 November and December
    - "How Has the Hungarian Minority Been Treated in Romania since 1920?," handwritten draft
    - "How Peace Lost?," handwritten draft
    - "Hungary and the Problem of Nationalities, Notes on," typewritten draft, 1970 August 13
    - "Igy nem marad..." (It will not last this way...), handwritten notes
    - "Independent Hungary," proclamation, New York, printed leaflet; radio speech on the BBC (explanation of the proclamation), mimeographed typescript in Hungarian; Movement of Independent Hungary, Minutes of the Executive Committee, Washington, D.C., 1941 September 27, October 2
    - "Indulunk!" (Let us go!), published article, 1951 February 9
    - "Intelligence Test for Law Makers and Columnists," handwritten notes
    - "The International Organization for Free Enterprise, Memorandum on," typescript, 1960 July 28
    - "A kiegyezes szaz ev tavlatabol" (The compromise, viewed hundred years later), published article, 1968 January 27
    - Letters to the Editor, New York Times
      - Undated
      - 1959
    - "Lucza-napi elmelkedes" (Lucza-Day reflections), typescript
    - "The Mediterranean Community," memorandum with two attachments, typescript, 1960 July 28
    - "Nem, nem, soha!" (No, No, Never!), published article in two parts and photocopy of a typescript, 1970 March 22 and 29
    - "New Terminology for Surrender. Decline and Fall of American Democracy," handwritten notes
    - "On Economic and Financial Relations between the U.S.A. and Egypt," memorandum, carbon copy typescript, 1957 December 20
    - "Oreg Dipi notaja az Uj Vilagrol" (Old D.P.'s song about the New World), handwritten, 1943 Christmas
    - Press statement on the Danube Valley and self-determination published in Uj Europa, Munich, 1970 June
      Eckhardt's five points excerpted in Hungarian.
    - "Soviet Colonialism, Memorandum on," carbon copy typescript, 1960 July 29
    - "The Soviet Master Plan for World Domination," unpublished essay, typescript, 1947 October
    - "Subsistence Farming in Latin America, Memorandum on," unpublished essay, handwritten and typewritten copies
    - "Trianon, Peace Treaty of," handwritten notes in Hungarian, 1971 September
    - "Ujevi Uzenet, 1970" (New Year's Day Message, 1970), published article, typewritten manuscript, and commentaries published in several Hungarian newspapers, 1970 January
    - "Uzenet a vilag magyarsaganak" (Message to the Hungarians of the World), clipping from the National Guard Yearbook, and the original manuscript in Hungarian, 1970
    - "Zsidokerdes" (The Jewish Question), handwritten notes
- SUBJECT FILE, 1941-1972 (Boxes 5-24)
  Clippings, correspondence, essays, and memoranda, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abortion - Hungary [See also: Kapotsy, Bela] (Box 5)
  - Acheson, Dean
  - Aczel, Gyorgy
  - Aczel, Tamas
  - Adenauer, Konrad
  - Adonyi, Ferenc. "A karpatmedence hadaszati jelentosege, 4 vazlattal" (The strategic meaning of the Carpathian Valley, with 4 sketches), unpublished essay, typescript, 1951 January 1
  - Africa
  - African leaders
  - African nationalism
  - Afro-Americans
  - Agh, Laszlo
  - Agnew, Spiro
  - Agricultural laborers - United States
  - Agriculture
    - Communist countries
    - Hungary, (5 folders)
    - Unites States
  - Aehrenthal, Count Aloys Lexa (Box 6)
  - Alexander I, King of Yugoslavia - Assassination, 1934
  - American Hungarian Committee for Defense of Hungary, founded June 20, 1957, Washington, D.C., memoranda, proclamations, printed and mimeographed in English and Hungarian, 1957, 1959
  - American Hungarian Federation, founded in 1907
    - Bylaws, 1947 November 17
    - Membership lists, 1941-1942
    - Official declaration (Let Us Gather under the Unfurled Flag!), 1941
    - Resolution, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1941 November 27
    - The American Hungarian Federation to the People of Hungary, Detroit, Michigan, 1942 April 9
    - Memorial submitted to the White House, 1942 June 4-5
    - Letter to the President of the United States, and Answer from the White House, 1944 June 5, 8
    - Statement on the establishment of the temporary new Hungarian Government and names of the members of the government, 1945
    - The Voice of the People. "Truth about Hungary," by Grace Fleming, editor, Portland Press Herald, Portland, Maine, 1945 January 30
    - Solemn protest against the Hungarian Peace Treaty, Washington, D.C., 1947 January 30
    - Memorandum to the Secretary of State concerning the Hungarian problem, 1947 June
    - Proclamation to the Hungarian People, Chicago, Illinois, 1947 November 18
    - Resolution, 1958
    - Appeal to the United Nations General Assembly, 1958 August 13
    - White House reply to the President of the American Hungarian Federation, 1959 May 7
    - "Valasz a szirenhangokra" (Reply to the siren's voices), 1963 February
    - Protest. Reverend Andras Hamza's statement about Hungary, 1963 November 8
    - Resolution, 1964
    - Memorandum to Henry Kissinger, 1969 March 21
    - Agenda of the Director's Meeting, 1970 April 29
    - "Blueprint for a Neutralization of Central Europe,", 1971 February
    - Invitations for memorial celebrations, 1971-1972
    - Meeting of the Directors celebrating the 65th anniversary of the founding of the Federation, 1972 January 1
  - American Hungarian Library and Historical Society, Inc. - List of books donated by the Archduke Otto von Habsburg, and related correspondence in German
  - American Hungarian Student Association, meeting of the Executive Council and Supervisory Committee, New York, 1957 December 27-30
  - American way of life
  - Americans of Central-Eastern European Descent, the Conference of, 1957-1959, 1961
  - Amerikai Magyar Reformatus Egyhaz puspoki tanacsanak hatarozata (Decision of the Episcopal Council of the American Hungarian Reformed Church), Perth Amboy, New Jersey, 1963 November
  - Amerikai Magyar Reformatus Lelkeszegyesulet (American Hungarian Reformed Clergyman's Association)
  - "Angol tarsutasok vakmero hazugsagai Magyarorszagrol" (English fellow-travelers' reckless lies about Hungary), Hungaria, 1952 September 12
  - Angola
  - Anti-communism
  - Arab countries
  - Asia
  - Asociacion Cultural Argentina pro Hungria